{"data":[{"question":"The professor demanded that our reports ___ before the second class was over.","a":"would be handed over","b":"must hand over","c":"must be handed over","d":"be handed over","answer":"4","explain":"\n- The Subjunctive is used to emphasize urgency or importance. It is used after certain expressions: \n - S+ advise \/ask\/to command\/demand\/desire\/insist\/propose\/recommend\/request\/suggest\/ urge (that) + S + (would) Infinitive ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"69","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"If Jeffery ___ to the teacher attentively, he ___ the answer to the question now.","a":"listened, would know","b":"had listened, would have known","c":"had listened, would know","d":"listened, would have known","answer":"3","explain":"\n- Conditional Sentence Type 2 and 3: used to talk about things that didn't happened in the past which result in consequence at present \n+ Form: if + Past Perfect, would + Verb","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"69","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"The villagers _________ have lived through the war years without the volunteers' help.","a":"wouldn't","b":"couldn't","c":"mustn't","d":"shouldn't","answer":"2","explain":"\n- Could have PP: used to say that something was a possibility in the past, but did not actually happen","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"69","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"___ it rain tomorrow, we would have to put off the visit to the farm .","a":"Should","b":"Were","c":"Will","d":"Would","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Sometimes conditional forms are inverted as a means of sounding more formal. In this case, the conditional 'if' is dropped and the inverted forms takes the place of the 'if clause' \n- Inversion clause: auxiliary + subject + main verb","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"69","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"The guard at the door insisted that every visitor ___ the rules.","a":"obey","b":"obeys","c":"would obey","d":"will obey","answer":"1","explain":"\n- The Subjunctive is used to emphasize urgency or importance. It is used after certain expressions: \n -S+ advise \/ask\/to command\/demand\/desire\/insist\/propose\/recommend\/request\/suggest\/ urge (that) + S + (would) Infinitive ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"69","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"The two strangers who met first time talked as if they ___ old friends for years.","a":"would be","b":"should be","c":"had been","d":"have been","answer":"3","explain":"\n- Clauses that start with as if\/as though express unreality, improbability or doubt if they are followed by an unreal tense \n- The past perfect tense is used if we talk about an unreal situation in the present","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"69","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"If it _________ for the hurricane, our club ___ the mountain last Saturday.","a":"were not, could climb","b":"were not, could have climbed","c":"had not been, could climb","d":"had not been, could have climbed","answer":"4","explain":"\n- Conditional Sentence Type 3: used to talk about things that didn't happened in the past and the consequence if they had happened \n+ Form: if + Past Perfect, would + have + Past Participle ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"69","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"If my car ___ out of gas, I would have arrived there.","a":"shouldn't run","b":"didn't run","c":"hadn't run","d":"haven't run","answer":"3","explain":"\n- Conditional Sentence Type 3: used to talk about things that didn't happened in the past and the consequence if they had happened \n+ Form: if + Past Perfect, would + have + Past Participle ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"69","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"If Josh had not worn his dark glasses, he _________ by the police.","a":"might have been recognized","b":"might be recognized","c":"was to have been recognized","d":"would have recognized","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Might have PP: used as the past tense of 'may' when reporting that someone talked or thought about the possibility of something ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"69","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"If we had known that Nancy had been scheduled to arrive today, we ___ at the airport.","a":"might met","b":"may have met","c":"might have met","d":"may met","answer":"3","explain":"\n- Might have PP: used as the past tense of 'may' when reporting that someone talked or thought about the possibility of something ","category":"1","subcategorylv1":"69","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"}]}